peter sankiewicz

psankiewicz@icloud.com

senior software engineer

https://github.com/petsan https://www.linkedin.com/in/petsan

20+ years of proven experience designing, implementing and testing complex software solutions for new products. Dedicated to elegance and quality in code. Accomplished coder, team player, excellent communicator, creative problem-solver, experienced leader. Organized, self-motivated, and passionate about learning.

skill areas

- Python, Java, JavaScript, Selenium
- Docker, Kubernetes
- Test Planning, Automation, Analysis, and Reporting
- Google Cloud Platform
- Concourse CI
- Agile, Scrum, Kanban, TDD
- RESTful APIs, Clean Architecture
- Leadership

professional experience

Vulcan, Inc.

Senior Engineer • 2001 — 2019

Software Development Engineer in Test — Responsible for automated testing for an iOS and browser based application to playback video assets.

- Built an automated testing framework based on existing test plans.
- Supported manual QA efforts with automation and test analysis.
- Analized app performance metrics.
- Ensured stability of software releases and acted as the Release Manager.

Lead Quality & AV/IT Engineer — Lead engineer responsible for the quality and performance for a multi-million dollar custom projection location based entertainment project.

- Produced and executed extensive test plans, test automation and test reports accross a wide range of custom hardware and software.
- Envisioned, designed, and oversaw the production of a custom server to efficiently play back video and video games on four 4K projectors at 80GBps.
- Produced, converted and assesed 8K-60 video streams, with various encoding and quality settings.
- Participated in multi-day builds of the Holodome, including at TED 2019 in Vancouver B.C..
- Development tools: Python, Unity, Selenium, Windows UWP, iOS, Android
- Program Management tools: JIRA, TestRails, LiquidPlanner, Agile, Scrum

DevOps Tools Engineer — Developed cloud infrastructure automation for global, multi-million dollar Philanthropy projects. Enabled reliable, repeatable deployments to production environments on multiple cloud providers.

- Implemented Kubernetes deployments for containerized applications in the cloud.
- Built continuous integration/continuous deployment pipelines on Concourse CI.
- Built cloud-agnostic tooling to automate infrastructure provisioning.
- Development tools: Python, Docker, Kubernetes, Google Cloud Platform, Azure Cloud, AWS, Concourse CI, Pair-Programming

Software Engineer — Full-stack web devloper on a cross-platform web application.

- Performed feature engineering.
- Development tools: Django, JavaScript, JQuery, PostrgreSQL, node.js, angular.js.

• Co-ordinated with other engineers to ensure software stability.

Lead Quality Engineer — Led the quality efforts for the Wildlife Conservation Initiatives for the \$100M Vulcan Philanthropy group.

- Successfully engaged with multiple stakeholders on the value of quality engineering practices.
- Implemented team-wide initiatives for learning.
- Successfully released multiple products across multiple release launches.
- Thoroughly debugged issues found before submitting tickets.
- Led the team in Scrum implementation.

Lead Quality Engineer — Led the testing efforts on multiple world-wide deployments.

- Release management of multiple simultanous products across a world-wide collection of properties.
- Participated in the initial installation and led the testing effort of AV hardware on the MY Octopus Mega-Yacht.
- Reported on testing efforts to stakeholders.

Microsoft, Inc. (Contractor)

Lead Quality Engineer • 1997 — 2001

Windows NT Site Server — Responsible for creating, updating, and executing automated test scripts accross multiple servers in a laboratory setting.

- Designed and executed automated test cases.
- Focused on testing TCP/IP and LDAP.
- Reported on testing results.

Windows 98 — Led a team of Quality Engineers.

- Led a team of QA Engineers in structured testing methodologies, verification and reporting.
- Designed and executed test plans of the Windows 98 network stack.
- Designed and executed test plans for Windows 98 internationalized in German.

Keane, Inc.

Windows 95 Support Engineer • 1995 — 1997

Phone Support Engineer II

- Troubleshot support calls not solved by first queue.
- Focused on the Windows 95 networking stack.
- Entered bugs into Microsoft's bug database when encountered.

Phone Support Engineer I

- Troublshot support calls from end-users.
- Entered call logs into the database.
- Transferred calls to next queue when necessary.

River Riders, Inc.

Whitewater Rafting Guide • 2002 — 2007

Guided whitewater rafting crews.

- Safely guided whitewater rafts crews down the Wenatchee river.
- Prepared lunch for guests and crew.
- Maintained rafts and other equipment.

education

Capella University

BS, IT — Information Assurance & Security • Magna Cum Laude • 2010 — 2015

University of Washington

BS, Pre-Med (1994 —)

Code Fellows

Full stack web development bootcamp

tech community

- Holodome at TED in Vancouver, 2019
- StarWest Conference
- Application Lifecycle Management Conference
- Attended other conferences